<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Learnings on Background Process </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://backgroundprocess.com/learning/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Tim Kuhlman</author>
    
    <updated>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 21:54:04 MDT</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo</title>
      <link>http://backgroundprocess.com/learning/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 21:54:04 MDT</pubDate>
      <author>Tim Kuhlman</author>
      <guid>http://backgroundprocess.com/learning/hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like static generated sites, simple, effective and secure. I love github pages as it gets the job done easily and well. Jekyll is a natural fit
with github pages and was a great way to start building a blog. However recently &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; has caught my attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to switch to Hugo for a few different reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I like the clean directory layout better with Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I want disqus, rss, tags, some easy social sharing links and google analytics. All of that is possible with Jekyll but some of these are much easier to setup with Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
- It continues to have all the static site generation goodness and allows me to keep working with markdown and yaml.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not that I have the greatest visual appeal to the blog now but a refreshed look is still welcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of those reasons I am learning golang, which happens to be why I haven&amp;rsquo;t blogged in awhile but also adds some appeal to Hugo. The simple single binary installation
is great compared to dealing with ruby gems. That along with the ability to explore the code while I learn golang are really the reasons I first started looking at Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t all great with Hugo, it does need a separate git repo which is a bit of a pain. Luckily the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog&#34;&gt;github pages tutorial&lt;/a&gt;
does a great job at explaining a few different git subrepo techniques and scripts to minimize the pain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to Blog!</title>
      <link>http://backgroundprocess.com/learning/time-to-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 22:17:36 MDT</pubDate>
      <author>Tim Kuhlman</author>
      <guid>http://backgroundprocess.com/learning/time-to-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently in my normal reading I ran across this
&lt;a href=&#34;http://nathanmarz.com/blog/you-should-blog-even-if-you-have-no-readers.html&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; by Nathan Marz expounding
the merits of a blog. Not long after reading this and letting it percolate through my mental background process I
begun a class on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/&#34;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt;, titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/course/learning&#34;&gt;Learning How to Learn&lt;/a&gt;.
In this midst of this class I realized that the benefits of blogging Nathan promotes are essentially
ways to enhance your day to day learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m convinced, I will join the ranks of bloggers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While debating with myself on whether this was a worthwhile project I decided my primary goals for a blog are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To take ideas and develop them fully.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To improve my written communication skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To sharpen my brain in regards to forming and analyzing arguments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/course/learning&#34;&gt;Learning How to Learn&lt;/a&gt; course has taught me that writing a blog can be a great tool
for attaining those learning goals in a number of ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First the very name of this blog is a reflection that I expect to primarily get the ideas for blog topics from the periods of
diffuse thinking in my life. The times when I intensely focused may result in some blog posts but generally when I am focused
the goal and outcome are not to create a blog post. The blog is a great outlet for the thoughts from my diffuse thinking, allowing
me to more fully explore such ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I begin to explore ideas for a post I will need to practice recall which will help me to better remember the topics in my recent
learning. Recalling the various aspects for a post and attempting to organize them into a coherent whole will assist me in forming
mental chunks which are the basis of so much learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly sending my ideas out to the world is not something to be done without first testing and validating the thoughts. Self testing
of an idea or topic being learned is an important learning skill.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
